VISHWA DEEP GHIMIRE

vishwadeep.ghimire@gmail.com

Experienced Software Engineer with 7+ years of experience in a broad range of industries as a Full Stack Engineer, and as an Android developer. Proficient in 10+ Programming languages, and frameworks.

Languages: Java, RxJava, Kotlin, JavaScript, TypeScript **Web:** HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, React

Web Services: RESTful

Web/App Servers: Apache Tomcat, NodeJS

Frameworks: Spring (MVC, Boot, Security, AOP, IOC, DI), Hibernate, Grails, Angular

Databases: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Realm, Redis, Elasticsearch

Design Patterns: Singleton, Prototype, Observer, Factory

SDLC: Agile-Scrum, Waterfall, TDD, RAD **Cloud:** AWS (Lambda, S3 Bucket), Azure

Tools: JUnit, Mockito, Espresso, Jenkins, Maven, Gradle, Npm, Webpack, IntelliJ, Eclipse, STS, Android Studio, Xcode, WebStorm, PyCharm, WebSocket, Docker, Swagger, Zipkin, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Vault,

SAML

Platforms: Mac OS, Windows, Linux, Firebase, AWS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

7-Eleven, Irving, Texas, USA · March 2023 - Current Software Developer

- Creating and maintaining mobile applications using Java, Kotlin and React Native that are production-level, and that meet the highest standards of quality.
- Conducting research and prototyping for mobile software solutions that solve retail problems.
- Collaborating and partnering with peers from various disciplines, such as machine learning, computer vision, and systems design.
- Delivering high-quality research, innovation, and engineering work on time.

<u>Technologies Used:</u> Java, Kotlin, JavaScript, TypeScript, React Native, Node, Python, Angular, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka

ZAKIPOINT HEALTH, Kathmandu, Nepal · May 2020 - April 2022 Senior Software Engineer

- Designed and implemented microservices architectures using Java and Spring (Boot, Security).
- Developed and maintained REST APIs including implementing security measures such as OAuth, JWT, and SAML.
- Integrated microservices with databases such as MySQL, and MongoDB using technologies like Hibernate and JPA.
- Used containerization technologies like Docker and Kubernetes to manage the deployment and scaling of microservices, including setting up container clusters and deploying containers to them.
- Integrated microservices with message brokers such as Kafka to enable asynchronous communication and event-driven architectures.
- Integrated microservices with client-side applications built with technologies like Angular, and TypeScript.
- Worked on US healthcare data (claim, benefit, provider, medical, pharmacy) and integrated third party services to fetch Insurance Card (Red Card API), Benefit Document (EOB), Pratter API (Price Transparency API), EDI 270/271, and EDI 276/276 data format.

- Created custom analytics service for web and mobile applications to measure and optimize user acquisition, engagement, and app crashes.
- Built and deployed microservices to cloud platforms such as AWS using tools like Lambda including setting up deployment pipelines and monitoring processes.
- Built chatbot service using Azure Bot Service and QnA Maker, and MS BotFramework DirectLine.

<u>Technologies Used:</u> Spring (Boot, Security, JPA, DI, AOP), Hibernate, OAuth, JWT, SAML, React, React Native, Angular, TypeScript, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS (S3, Lambda), Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka, Zipkin, Redis, Elasticsearch, Azure (Bot Service, QnA Maker), MS BotFramework DirectLine,

JAVRA SOFTWARE, Lalitpur, Nepal · Jan 2018 - Apr 2020 Software Engineer

- Designed and implemented REST APIs using Java, and Spring framework technologies.
- Worked with persistence frameworks such as Hibernate to manage the mapping of objects to a database and to operations on the data.
- Implemented security measures using technologies such as OAuth and JWT for authentication and authorization of API requests.
- Worked with databases such as MySQL to store and retrieve data for the microservices.
- Developed digital notice board system and anonymous reporting tool.
- Integrated the microservices with other systems using technologies such as Kafka for asynchronous communication.

<u>Technologies Used:</u> Spring (Boot, Security, JPA, DI, AOP), Hibernate, OAuth, JWT, MySQL, JavaScript, NativeScript, TypeScript, Angular, Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka, Zipkin

VIS NETWORK, Kathmandu, Nepal ·May 2017- Jan 2018 Software Developer

- Developed and integrated RESTful APIs with functional applications using Java, Spring, Hibernate.
- Implemented Oauth, JWT, Spring Security for authorization and authentication.
- Integrated OAuth-based login which supports user login using Google and Facebook credentials.
- Created persona-based login system for Nanny Sharing and LoFo(Lost & Found) apps.
- The front-end UI created using Angular and integrated with RESTful service.
- Applied Google Geolocation API for searching items in LoFo app.
- Contributed to development of one-to-one chat system with push notifications between LoFo users.

<u>Technologies Used:</u> Spring (Boot, Security, JPA, DI, AOP), Hibernate, OAuth, JWT, MySQL, JavaScript, Angular

YELLOW NEPAL, Kathmandu, Nepal · Aug 2016 - May 2017 Mobile App Developer

- Developed Android app Nidarr, which provides individuals with a secure, private platform to stay connected, report gender-based violence, and maximize safety to prevent violence.
- Implemented full stack Android applications for online language testing, clipboard management, and the official Nepal Tourism Board app.

Technologies Used: Java, SQLite, Realm, Firebase

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

(In progress via distance education; expected completion December 2024)
Maharishi International University – Fairfield, Iowa

Key Courses: Fundamental Programming Practices; Modern Programming Practices; Algorithm; Web Application Programming; Software Architecture; Enterprise Architecture

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology (2016) Nepal College of Information Technology – Lalitpur, Nepal